## **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Email: - subhajitnag23@gmail.comsubhajitnag@yahoo.in

Mobile no: - 9883995865/7980981485

## **Objective:**

To succeed in the geospatial industry through continued learning- in complex situations, visualizing problems, and creating geographic plans and solutions. To work in an organization where innovation, research and excellence is the way of life; where my potential will be fully utilized and where I can grow as an individual as well as a professional along with the growth of the organization.

### **Professional Summary**

$\square$ 6.6 years of	experie	nce in N	1apping,	, Geodata	abase -Sp	oatial A	nalysis,	report	prepara	tion 8
team leading.										
	·	_		_		_	_	_		

- Analysis in GIS and Remote Sensing
   – Image classification, Image Processing & Geological mapping.
- ☐ Ability to work **independently** and in a **team**, delivering high quality work.

### **Area of Interest:**

☐ Remote Sensing and GIS Applications

□ DBMS

☐ Field Work

### **GIS & RS Skills:**

Software: Arc GIS 9.3, 9.2,10& Above, ERDAS 9.3& 11&14 16 18,

Geometica (PCI) 12,15,16 & 17 Global Mapper.

## **Educational Qualifications**

 $\hfill\Box$  Post Graduate Diploma in **Remote Sensing & Geographical Information System (GIS)** Jadavpur University (Kolkata)

Year of Passing- 2012

☐ M.A in **Geography** 

Global Open University (Nagaland)

Year of Passing- 2014

☐ B.A in **Geography** 

Vinoba Bhave University (Hazaribagh)

Year of passing -2010

### **Certificate Course:**

☐ Diploma in Computer Application (DITA) in 2007

## **Professional Experience**

Organization : Global Business Solutions.

Period : June 2014 – Till Date

Role : GIS Engineer & GIS Consultant.

Organization: Stesalit Limited.

Period : Aug 2012 – June 2014

Role : GIS Survey Supervisor & GIS Executive.

## 1) Project Name: "Ortho-Rectification of High Resolution Satellite Data (Stereo/Tri-stereo) - Maharashtra State" of photogrammetric work under MahaBHUMI project

Client: Maharashtra Remote Sensing Applications Centre (MRSAC).

**Duration: Apr 2018 to Till date** 

Software Use: Erdas Imagine 2016 & 2018.

Arial triangulation & Bundle adjustment of all the individual blocks of Maharashtra.

DEM (LTF) editing of each & individual scenes & DSM creation.

Ortho photo creation & Mosaicing & Color balancing of all the blocks.

Seamless Mosaic of whole block.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Arial Triangulation.
- LTF editing in 3D.
- Ortho photo Creation.
- Mosaicing & Edge matching of blocks
- Communicate with MRSAC Representative during the work

### 2) Project Name: "Digitization of Mission IV Unpublished Reports Geological Survey of India"

Client: Geological Survey of India (GSI) Eastern Region, Saltlake Kolkata.

**Duration: Nov 2017 to Feb 2018** 

Role: GIS Support.

### 3) Project Name: "Ortho-Photo rectification of Cartosat-1 and Liss IV data".

Client:Odisha Space Applications Center (ORSAC).

**Duration:Oct 2016 to Oct 2017** 

Mosaicking all the individual tiles & scenes.

Ortho rectification of all the Scenes.

Pan sharping the Cartosat &Liss IV data

### **Responsibilities:**

- Handling all the work & 6 member's team during Production.
- Data QC after work.
- Data Integration in ORSAC.
  Communicate with ORSAC Representative during the work

# 4) Project Name: "GIS Implementation with Power ATLAS of EHT Tower Survey (O&M) In Entire Odisha by Odisha Space Applications Center. (ORSAC), Bhubaneswar".

Client:Odisha Space Applications Center (ORSAC) & Odisha Power Transmission Corporation Limited (OPTCL)

Duration: Dec 2015 to Feb 2018

Survey of EHT Towers (400KV, 220KV, 132KV) Using GPS.

Survey of Substation & Other Offices.GIS Database Creation Surveyed Offices & EHTs.

Land Use/Land Cover Mapping of the Power Corridor Running Over Length. Using CARTOSAT & PAN & LISS IV MX Satellite Data.

Land Use/Land Cover Mapping of Substations & Other Offices.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Handling the 6 member's team during mapping.
- Data QA/QC after Survey.
- GIS Plotting & Mapping QA/QC.
- GIS Database Creation.
- Data Integration in ORSAC.
- Work with Satellite Imagery in ORSAC & OPTCL.
- Communicate with OPTCL during the work.
- 5) Project Name: "Ortho-Photo rectification of World View-II PAN and Multispectral data".

Client: Odisha Space Applications Center (ORSAC).

Duration: Oct 2015 to Sept 2016

Mosaicking all the individual tiles & scenes of World View II data. Ortho rectification of all the PAN & Multispectral Scenes with Cartosat reference data. Pan sharping the World View-II Data PAN & Multispectral Image.

### **Responsibilities:**

- Handling all the work &8 member's team during Production.
- Data QC after work.
- Data Integration in ORSAC.
- Communicate with ORSAC Representative during the work.
- 6) Project Name: "Andhra Pradesh Forest Data& Census Data Integration with Different Types Of GIS Layers.".

Client: Andhra Pradesh Forest Dept.

**Duration: Aug 2015 to Oct 2015** 

7) Project Name: "Odisha Sampad Power Atlas Application Based Upon Different Types of GIS Layers"

Client: Odisha Space Applications Centre (ORSAC).

Duration: May 2015 to July 2017

### 8) Project Name: "West Bengal Fifth Irrigation Data Application"

Client: Dept. Of Science & Technology West Bengal.

**Duration: Mar 2015 to May 2015** 

9) Project Name: "Pilot Project for GIS Implementation with Power ATLAS of EHT Tower's (O&M) In the Jurisdiction Circle -Cuttack by Odisha Space Applications Center. (ORSAC), Bhubaneswar".

Client: Odisha Space Applications Center (ORSAC) & Odisha Power Transmission Corporation Limited (OPTCL).

### **Duration: June 2014 to Mar 2015**

Survey of EHT Towers (400KV, 220KV, 132KV) Using GPS.

Survey of Substation & Other Offices.GIS Database Creation Surveyed Offices & EHTs.

Land Use/Land Cover Mapping Of the Power Corridor Running Over Length. Using CARTOSAT & PAN & LISS IV MX Satellite Data.

Land Use/Land Cover Mapping Of Substations & Other Offices.

### Responsibilities:

- Handling all the work &the team during mapping.
- Data QC after Survey.
- GIS Plotting & Mapping.
- GIS Database Creation.
- Data Integration in ORSAC.
- Work with Satellite Imagery in ORSAC & OPTCL.
- Communicate with OPTCL during the work.

## 10) Project Name:" Updation of GIS Consumer Indexing and Asset Mapping by GPS Survey" Under R-APDRP Town area of MGVCL Jurisdiction.

**Client:** MGVCL (Madhya Gujarat Vij Company Limited)

### Duration: July 2013 to June 2014

The purpose of this project was updating of GIS mapping of entire power network of MGVCL. The MGVCL Company uses a standalone web application for the data updating. The company distributes electricity in five districts (Vadodara, Dahod, Panchmahal, kheda, and Anand) of Gujarat, and the total scenario updating through this web application.

This application through updating of newly added Substation, Tapping Point, HT Pole, HT line, DTR, Meter, Switch, Fuse, LT Pole, LT line, New Consumer in their exact location or any type of changes of their existing data are also updating.

#### Responsibilities:

- Handling all the work & the team in updation.
- Data updation QC.
- Data updation Reporting.
- Leading Field Survey of Pilot Town.
- Data Submission in MGVCL.
- Clint Entertainment & Meeting.
- Communicate with all the member of MGVCL during the work.

11) Project Name: "GIS Mapping of Entire Power Network in Nagaland (Including RGGVY

assets in separate layer)"

Client: Government of Nagaland (Department of Power).

**Duration: June 2013 to July 2013** 

12) Project Name: "REC Power Distribution Company Limited Uploading GIS Data with Hand Sketch SLD and Data Editing"

Client : **RECPDCL** (**Rajasthan**) **Duration**: **Apr 2013 June 2013** 

13) Project Name: "Slum Free City Plan under RAJIV AWAS YOJNA Raipur Chhattisgarh"

Client: MUNICIPLE CORPORATION OF RAIPUR.

Duration: Jan 2013 to Apr 2013

Preparation of spatial data & base map, application software to view and print GIS maps, asset codification, field data collection, asset meta data preparation (with geo-referencing), plotting of assets on base map.

14) Project Name: "Slum Free City Plan Under RAJIV AWAS YOJNA Korba Chhattisgarh"

Client: MUNICIPLE CORPORATION OF RAIPUR.

**Duration: Sept 2012 to Jan 2013** 

Preparation of spatial data & base map, application software to view and print GIS maps, asset codification, field data collection, asset meta data preparation (with geo-referencing), plotting of assets on base map.

### **Responsibilities:**

- GPS Data plotting;
- GIS Lane Mapping & Microplanning.
- CBO Formation,
- City Sanitation Plan (Korba).

### **Declaration:**

I hereby declare that the above mentioned particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Date –	/	/	_		
				Subhaiit Nag	